# Vivek Kumar Mohanty

## **Security Consultant**

Experienced software developer with a demonstrated history of working in the Identity and Access Management (IAM) domain which includes User Life Cycle Management, Application Onboarding, Role Management, Access Review, Policy Management. Skilled in Java, Python, SQL, and Data Structures.

#### $\sim$

vivek9237@protonmail.com

+91 8622028912



Bengaluru, India

in

linkedin.com/in/vivek9237

()

github.com/vivek9237

### **SKILLS**

Identity and Access

Core Java

SQL

Python

Shell Script

SailPoint IIQ

Lipux

GIT

Active Directory

RSA IG&L

Skill

JavaScript

Web-Development

### **LANGUAGES**

#### **English**

Full Professional Proficiency

Hindi

Native or Bilingual Proficiency

### **INTERESTS**

Music

Gaming

Coding

#### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

## **Consultant** RSA Security

11/2019 - Present Bengaluru

Project Experience

- Worked on RSA IG&L as a consultant on several projects to design and implement Joiner, Mover, and Leaver for our customers. Have worked on Access Reviews, Policy Management, various workflows, onboarded different type applications like - AD, Flatfile, Database, ServiceNow, O365, Web Service based application, etc.
- Worked on a custom solution for RSA IG&L to provide an option for Admin users to perform several operations such as attribute update, application onboarding, enable/disable accounts, profile picture update, etc. in bulk. Designed a framework that makes implementing bulk operation fast and keeps an audit track of operations in the database.
- Worked on a product development project which will evaluate cyber exposure in customer environments where various RSA products are deployed. This product will deliver cyber exposure details to the insurance company weekly.
- Worked on RSA NetWitness integration projects to collect logs from various products.
- Worked on RSA Archer and National Vulnerability Database (NVD) integration. This integration helps to detect vulnerable devices in an organization.

# **Application Security Engineer**Cognizant

06/2015 - 10/2019 Kolkata

Project Experience

- Worked on SailPoint IdentityIQ as a consultant to implement Life Cycle Events, Reviews, Application Onboarding, requirement analysis, solution design, implementation, production deployment.
- Worked on different rules to modify the incoming data before storing in IDM, form to grant adhoc user access, reporting, etc. Also Worked on IIQ to develop custom web-service Activity Collector.
- Worked on SailPoint Plugin, which provides a bulk approval facility without changing any OOTB IIQ code.
- Implemented Code and Configuration Management for clients in GIT, which supports working with multiple teams with multiple developers.
- Worked on Oracle Identity Management to develop event Handlers for various validations and operations in OIM. Used BI publisher for generating custom reports. Worked on Custom admin roles for various admin related activities.
- Provided knowledge transfer and post-production support activities.

#### **EDUCATION**

# **Bachelor of Technology in Electrical Engineering** C V Raman College of Engineering, Bhubaneswar

2011 - 2015